"Summoned to court to answer for the crimes
"Convoqué :! la cour pour répondre des crimes
"Arrive within the fortnight or be branded an enemy of the crown."
"Présentez—vous sous 15 jours ou devenez un ennemi de la couronne."
Poor Ned Stark.
Pauvre Ned Stark.
Brave man, terrible judgment.
Un homme courageux. mais d'un piètre jugement.
Attacking him was stupid.
C‘était stupide de I'atæquer.
Lannisters...
Les Lannister...
don‘t act like fools.
ne se comportent pas ainsi.
Are you going to say something clever?
As—tu quelque chose d'intelligent :! dire ?
Go on, say something clever.
Vas—y, dis quelque chose d'intelligent.
Oatelyn Stark took my brother.
Gatelyn Stark a enlevé mon frère.
- Why is he still alive? - Tyrion?
- Pourquoi est—il encore en vie ? - Tyﬁon ?
Ned Stark.
Ned Stark.
One of our men interfered,
Un de nos hommes est intervenu.
speared him through the leg before I could ﬁnish him.
il lui a transpercé la jambe avant que je ne puisse le tuer.
Why is he still alive?
Pourquoi est—il encore en vie ?
It wouldn‘t have been clean.
Ça n‘aurait pas été une mort digne.
Clean.
Digne.
You spend too much time worrying about what other people think of you.
Tu passes trop de temps a te soucier de ce que les autres pensent.
I could care less what anyone thinks of me.
Je me ﬁche de ce que les gens pensent de moi.
That's what you want people to think of you.
C‘est ce que tu veux que l'on pense de toi.
It's the truth.
C‘est la vérité.
When you hear them whispering "kingslayer" behind your back
Quand ils murmurent "régicide" dans ton dos,
doesn‘t it bother you?
ca ne te dérange pas ?
Of course it bothers me.
Bien sûr que ca me dérange.
A lion doesn‘t concern himself
Un lion ne se soucie pas
with the opinions of the sheep.
de l‘opinion des moutons.
I suppose I should be grateful that your vanity
Je devrais être heureux que ta vanité
got in the way of your recklessness.
ait entrave ton imprudence.
I'm giving you half of our forces -
Je te donne la moitié de nos forces,
30,000 men.
30 000 hommes.
You will bring them to Oatelyn Starks girlhood home
Tu les emmèneras a la maison d‘enfance de 0ateiyn Stark
and remind her that Lannisters
et tu lui rappelleras que les Lannister
pay their debts.
payent toujours leurs dettes.
He's a Lannister.
C‘est un Lannister.
He might be the lowest of the Lannisters, but he's one of us.
C‘est peut—être le plus bas des Lannister, mais c'est un des ndtres.
And every day that he remains a prisoner,
Plus longtemps il restera prisonnier.
the less our name commands respect.
moins notre nom inspirera le respect.
So the lion does concern himself with the opinions of...
Alors le lion se soucie de l‘opinion de...
No, that's not an opinion. It's a fact.
Non, ce n‘est pas une opinion. C‘est un fait.
If another house can seize one of our own
Si une autre Maison peut prendre l'un des ndtres
and hold him captive with impunity,
et le garder prisonnier impunément.
we are no longer a house to be feared.
les gens ne nous craindront plus.
Your mother‘s dead.
Ta mère est morte.
Before long I'll be dead.
Bientot. je mounai aussi.
And you...
Puis toi...
and your brother and your sister
puis ton frère et ta sœur
and all of her children.
et tous ses enfants.
All of us dead, all of us rotting in the ground.
Nous serons tous morts. nous pourﬁrom tous sous terre.
It's the family name that lives on.
C‘est le nom de famille qui survit.
It's all that lives on.
C‘est tout ce qui subsiste.
Not your personal glory, not your honour,
Pas ta gloire personnelle. pas ton honneur,
but family.
mais la famille.
Do you understand?
Tu comprends ?
You're blessed with abilities that few men possess.
Tu as la chance de posséder un talent que peu d'hommes ont.
You're blessed to belong to the most powerful family in the Kingdoms.
Tu as la chance d‘appartenir a la famille la plus puissante des couronnes.
And you're still blessed with youth.
Tu as la chance d‘être encore jeune.
And what have you done with these blessings, huh?
Et que fais—tu de cette chance ?
You've served as a gloriﬁed bodyguard for two kings -
Tu as servi de vulgaire garde du corps a deux rois,
one a madman, the other a drunk
un fou et un ivrogne.
The future of our family will be determined in these next few months.
L'avenir de notre famille va se jouer dans les prochains mois.
We could establish a dynasty that will last a thousand years.
Nous pourrions établir une dynastie qui durera des siècles.
Or we could collapse into nothing, as the Targaryens did.
Ou nous pourrions disparaitre, comme les Targaryens.
I need you to bmome the man you were always meant to be.
J'ai besoin que tu deviennes l‘homme que tu dois être.
Not next year. Not tomorrow.
Pas l‘année prochaine. Pas demain.
Now.
Aujourd'hui.
You're in pain.
Vous souffrez.
I've had worse, my lady.
J'ai connu pire, madame.
The South doesn't seem to agree with you.
Le Sud ne semble pas vous aller.
I know the tnrth Jon Arryn died for.
Je sais pourquoi Jon Arryn est mort.
Do you, Lord Stark?
Vraiment, Lord Stark ?
Is that why you called me here, to pose me riddles?
Vous m‘avez fait venir pour jouer aux devinettes ?
Has he done this before?
Vous a—t—il fait ça avant ?
Jaime would have killed him. My brother is worth a thousand of your friend.
Jaime l‘aurait tué.
Your brother...
Votre frère...
or your lover?
ou votre amant ?
The Targaryens wed brothers and sisters for 300 years
Les Targaryens se marient entre frères et sœurs depuis 300 ans
to keep bloodlines pure.
pour garder la lignée pure.
Jaime and l are more than brother and sister.
Jaime et moi sommes plus que frère et sœur.
We shared a womb.
Nous avons partagé un utérus.
We came into this world together. We belong together.
Nous sommes nés ensemble. Nous nous appartenons.
My son saw you with him.
Mon ﬁls vous a vu avec lui.
Do you love your children?
Aimez—vous vos enfants ?
- With all my heart. - No more than I love mine.
- De tout mon cœur. - Comme moi.
- And they're all Jaime's. - (Chuckles) Thank the gods.
- Et ils sont tous de Jaime. - Dieux merci.
In the rare event that Robert leaves his whores for long enough to stumble drunk into my bed,
Lorsque Robert laisse ses catins
I ﬁnish him off in other ways.
je le ﬁnis autrement.
- In the morning, he doesn't remember. - You've always hated him.
- Au réveil, il a tout oublié. - Vous l‘avez toujours détesté.
Hated him? I worshipped him.
Détesté ? Je l‘adorais.
Every girl in the Seven Kingdoms dreamed of him, but he was mine by oath.
Les ﬁlles des Sept Couronnes en révaient. mais il m‘appartenait par serment.
And when I ﬁnally saw him on our wedding day in the Sept of Baelor,
Quand je l'ai vu le jour de nos noces dans le Septuaire de Baelor,
lean and ﬁerce and black-bearded,
mince. féroce. avec sa barbe noire
it was the happiest moment of my life.
ce fut le plus beau jour de ma vie.
That night he crawled on top of me, stinking of wine,
Le soir, il s‘est glissé sur moi puant le vin,
and did what he did, what little he could do,
et il a fait le peu qu'il pouvait,
and whispered in my ear, "Lyanna."
et a murmuré dans mon oreille. "Lyanna."
Your sister was a corpse and l was a living girl
Votre sœur était morte. j‘étais vivante
and he loved her more than me.
et il l‘aimait plus que moi.
When the king returns from his hunt, I'll tell him the tnrth.
Quand le roi rentrera de la chasse. je lui dirai la vérité.
You must be gone by then - you and your children.
Vous serez loin. vous et vos enfants.
I will not have their blood on my hands.
Je ne veux pas de leur sang sur mes mains.
Go as far away as you can,
Partez aussi loin que vous le pouvez,
with as many men as you can.
emmenoz autant d'hommes que vous le pouvez.
Because wherever you go,
Parce que partout où vous irez.
Robert's wrath will follow you.
la fureur de Robert vous suivra.
And what of my wrath, Lord Stark?
Et ma fureur. Lord Stark ?
You should have taken the realm for yourself.
Vous auriez du vous emparer du royaume.
Jaime told me about the day King's Landing fell.
Jaime m‘a parlé de la prise de Port—Réal.
He was sitting in the Iron Throne and you made him give it up.
Il était assis sur le Trône de Fer et vous l‘avez fait descendre.
All you needed to do was climb the steps yourself.
II vous sufﬁsait de gravir les marches.
Such a sad mistake.
Quelle erreur navrante.
I've made many mistakes in my life...
J'ai commis beaucoup d‘erreurs dans ma vie...
but that wasn't one of them.
mais ce n'en était pas une.
Oh, but it was.
Mais c'en était une.
When you play the game of thrones, you win...
Au jeu des trônes, il faut vaincre...
or you die.
ou périr.
There is no middle ground.
Il n‘y a pas de moyen terme.
Oh, yesl Oh, yesl
Oh, oui I Oh, oui I
No, no, no, nol
Non, non, non, non |
Is that what they teach you up in the North?
C‘est ce qu‘ils vous apprennent dans le Nord ?
And you - wherever you're from -
Et toi, d'où que tu sois,
do you have any idea how ridiculous you sound?
te rends—tu compte du son que tu émets ?
Either of you understand a thing that I'm saying?
Vous comprenez ce que je dis ?
Yes, my lord.
Oui. monseigneur.
Lets start over, shall we?
Reprenons depuis le début.
You be the man...
Toi. tu seras l'homme...
and you be the woman.
et toi, tu seras la femme.
Well, go ahead.
Allez-y.
Slowly.
Doucement.
You're not fooling them. They just paid you.
Ils ne sont pas dupes. Ils viennent de vous payer.
They know it's all just an act.
Ils savent que c'est de la comédie.
Your job is to make them forget what they know.
Votre travail est de leur faire oublier ce qu‘ils savent.
Now, that takes time.
Et cela prend du temps.
You need to...
Vous devez...
easeinto it.
vous glisser dedans.
Go ahead.
Vas—y.
Easeinto it.
Glisse—toi dedans.
He's winning you over in spite of yourself.
II vous emporte malgré vous.
You're starting to like this.
Vous commeneez a aimer cela.
He wants to believe you.
Il veut bien vous croire.
He's enjoyed his cock since he was old enough to play with it. Why shouldn't you?
Il aime sa queue depuis qu'il joue avec.
He knows he's better than other men.
Il sait qu'il est meilleur que les autres hommes.
He's always known it deep down inside. Now he has proof.
Il l‘a toujours su. Maintenant, il en a la preuve.
He's so good,
II est si bon,
he's reaching something deep inside of you that no one even knew was there,
il atteint quelque chose en vous dont personne ne connaissait l‘ustence,
overcoming your very nature.
en surmontant votre nature.
Why don't you join us, my lord?
Joignez—vous donc a nous. monseigneur.
I'm saving myself for another.
Je me réserve pour une autre.
What she doesn't know won't hurt her.
Ce qu'elle ignore ne la blessera pas.
- A stupid saying. - (Moans)
Un dicton idiot.
What we don't know is usually what gets us killed.
Ce que nous ignorons est souvent ce qui nous tue.
She must be very beautiful.
Elle doit être très belle.
No, not really. lmpewable bloodlines though.
Non, pas vraiment. Des traits parfaits toutefois.
I do believe my lord's in love.
Je crois que monseigneur est amoureux
For many years. Most of my life, really.
Pendant des années. La plus grande partie de ma vie, en fait.
Play with her arse.
Joue avec son cul.
And she loved me too.
Et elle m‘a aimé aussi.
l was her little conﬁdant, her plaything.
J'étais son conﬁdent. son eemarade.
She could tell me anything, anything at all.
Elle pouvait tout me dire. absolument tout.
She told me about all the horses that she liked,
Elle m‘a parlé des chevaux qu'elle aimait.
the castle that she wanted to live in
du château où elle voulait vivre
and the man that she wanted to marry -
et de l‘homme qu'elle voulait épouser,
a Northerner... with a jaw like an anvil.
un homme du Nord... avec une mâchoire comme une enclume.
I mean, why not? I'd read all the stories.
Pourquoi pas ? J'avais lu toutes les histoires.
The little hero always beats the big villain in all the stories.
Le petit héro l‘emporte toujours sur le grand vilain dans les histoires.
In the end, she wouldn't even let him kill me.
À la ﬁn, elle ne l‘a méme pas laissé me tuer.
"He's just a boy," she said.
"C'est juste un enfant," a—t—elle dit.
"Please don't hurt him."
"Sii te plait. ne lui fait pas mal."
So he gave me a nice little soar to remember him by, and off they went.
Il m‘a laissé une jolie petite cicatrice en souvenir. et ils sont partis.
Is she still married to him?
Est—elle toujours son épouse ?
Oh, no. He got himself killed before the wedding...
Non. Il s‘est fait tué avant le mariage...
..and she ended up with his brother, an even more impressive specimen.
..et elle a épousé son frère, un spécimen encore plus impressionnant.
She loves him, I'm afraid.
Elle l‘aime. malheureusement.
And why wouldn't she? I mean, who could compare to him?
Et pourquoi ne I'aimerait—elle pas ? Qui pourrait se mesurer a lui ?
- He's just so... - (Shrieks and moans)
II esttrop...
..good.
..bien.
Do you know what I learned, losing that duel?
Sais—tu ce que j'ai appris en perdant ce duel ?
I learned that I'll never win, not that way.
J'ai appris que je ne gagnerai jamais. pas de cette façon.
That's their game,
C‘est leur jeu.
their rules.
leurs règles.
I'm not going to ﬁght them.
Je ne vais pas me battre contre eux
I'm going to fuck them. That's what I know.
Je vais les baiser. C‘est ce que je sais faire.
That's what I am.
C‘est ce que je suis.
And only by admitting what we are can we get what we want.
En admettant qui je suis. j‘aurai ce que je veux.
And what do you want?
Et que voulez—vous ?
Oh, everything, my dear.
Tout. ma chère.
Everything there is.
Absolument tout.
Now wash yourselves. Both of you are working tonight.
A présent, allez-vous laver. Vous travaillez ce soir.
You're a very lucky girl. Do you know that?
Tu as beaucoup de chance. tu sais ?
Where I come from, we don't show mercy to criminals.
D‘où je viens, on n‘a aucune pitié pour les criminels.
if someone like you attacked a little lord...
D‘où je viens, si quelqu'un comme toi attaquait un petit seigneur...
at low tide we'd lay you on your back on the beach,
A marée descendante. on tallongerait sur la plage sur le dos,
your hands and feet chained to four stakes.
les mains et les pieds attachés a quatre piquets.
The sea would come in closer and closer.
La mer remonterait de plus en plus près.
You'd see death creeping towards you a few inches at a time.
Tu venais la mort approcher a pas lents.
Where is it you come from?
D‘où venez—vous ?
The Iron Islands.
Des Îles de Fer.
They far away?
C‘est loin ?
You've never heard of the Iron Islands?
Tu n'as jamais entendu parler des Îles de Fer ?
Trust me, you've never heard where I'm from neither.
Croyez—moi, vous n‘avez jamais entendu parler d'où je Viens non plus.
"Trust me, my lord."
"Croyez—moi. monseigneur."
You're not living in the wildemess anymore.
Tu ne vis plus dans la forêt.
ln civilised lands, you refer to your betters
Dans notre monde, tu parles a tes supérieurs
by their proper titles.
en utilisant leurs titres.
- And what's that? - Lord.
- Et c'est quoi ? - Monseigneur.
Why?
Pourquoi ?
What do you mean, why?
Que veux—tu dire. pourquoi ?
My father is Balon Greyjoy, Lord of the Iron Islands.
Mon père est Balon Greij, Seigneur des Îles de Fer.
What's that got to do with you?
Quel rapport avec vous ?
If your father's lord,
Si votre père est un seigneur,
how can you be lord too?
comment pouvez—vous étre un seigneur ?
No, you...
Non, tu...
Are you having a go at me? Is that it?
Tu te moques de moi ? C‘est ça ?
I just don't understand how you southemers do things.
Je ne comprends pas les coutumes des gens du Sud.
- I'm not a southemer. - You're from south of the Wall.
- Je ne suis pas du Sud. - Vous étes du sud du Mur.
That makes you a southemer to me.
Vous étes du Sud pour moi.
You're an impudent little wench, aren't you?
Tu es une jeune effrontée. n'est—ce pas ?
Couldn't say, my lord.
Je ne sais pas, monseigneur.
Don't know what "impunent" means.
Je ne sais pas ce que signiﬁe "'effrondé“.
Impudent.
Eﬁronté.
It means rude, disrespectful.
Cela signiﬁe grossier, irrespectueux
Do you want to lose that chain?
Veux—tu te débarrasser de ces chaînes ?
Theon Greyjoyl
Theon Greij I
The lady is our guest.
La dame est notre invitée.
I thought she was our prisoner.
Je croyais qu'elle était prisonnière.
Are the two mutually exclusive in your experience?
Les deux sont—ils incompatibles selon vous ?
Chances are I won't be nearby the next time that happens.
Il est fort probable que je ne sois pas la la prochaine fois.
I'm used to worse than him.
J'ai connu pire que lui.
I'm used to men who could chew that boy up
J'ai connu des hommes qui écraseraient ce garçon
and pick their teeth with his bones.
et se curaient les dents avec ses os.
Why did you come here?
Pourquoi étes—vous venue ici ?
Didn't mean to come here.
Je ne voulais pas venir ici.
Meant to get much further south than this.
Je voulais aller beaucoup plus au sud.
As far south as south goes,
Le plus loin possible au sud,
before the long night comes.
avant que la longue nuit n‘arrive.
Why? What are you afraid 0|?
Pourquoi ? De quoi as—tu peur ?
There's things that sleep in the day and hunt at night.
II «ste des créatures qui donnent le jour et chassent la nuit.
- Owls and shadowcats... - I'm not talking about owls and shadowcats.
Chouettes, lynx . .
The things you speak of -
Les créatures dont tu parles
they've been gone for thousands of years.
ont disparu depuis des siècles.
They wasn't gone, old man.
Elles n'ont pas disparu, Vieil homme.
They was sleeping.
Elfes donnaient.
And they ain't sleeping no more.
Et elles ne donnent plus.
(Sanrwell) I miss girls.
Les ﬁlles me manquent.
Not even talking to them. I never talked to them.
Pas leur parler. Je ne leur parlais jamais.
Just looking at them,
Juste les regarder.
hearing them giggle.
les entendre rire.
Don't you miss girls?
Les ﬁlles ne te manquent pas ?
Riders.
Des cavaliers.
The horn. We have to blow the horn.
La come. Nous devons soufﬂer la corne.
Why is he alone?
Pourquoi est—il seul ?
One blast for a ranger returning,
Un coup pour un patrouilleur qui rentre,
two for wildlings,
deux pour les sauvageons,
- three for... - There's no rider.
- trois pour... - Il n‘y a pas de cavalier.
- (Neighs) - Whoa, boy, whoa.
Tout doux. mon garçon. tout doux
That's my Uncle Benjen's horse.
C‘est le cheval de mon oncle Benjen.
Where's my uncle?
Où est mon oncle ?
Nedl
Nedl
It's Robert. We were hunting...
C‘est Robert. Nous chassions...
a boar...
un sanglier...
shown you how to be a man.
t‘apprendre a étre un homme.
I was never meant to be a father.
Je n‘ai jamais eu la ﬁbre paternelle.
Go on.
Va—t'en.
You don't want to see this.
Tu ne veux pas voir ca.
My fault.
C‘est ma faute.
Too much wine, missed my thrust.
Trop de vin, j'ai manqué mon coup.
(Robert) It stinks.
Ça pue.
It stinks like death.
Ça pue la mort.
Don't think I can't smell it.
Va pas croire que je ne la sens pas.
I paid the bastard back. Ned.
Je l'ai fait payer ce salopard, Ned.
I drove my knife right through his brain.
Je lui ai planté mon couteau dans la cervelle.
You ask 'em if I didn't. Ask 'eml
Demande-leur si c'est vrai. Demande-leur I
I want the funeral feast to be the biggest the Kingdoms ever saw.
Que les obsèques soient les plus grandes que les Couronnes aient jamais connues.
And I want everyone to taste the boar that got me.
Et je veux que chacun goûte au sanglier qui m‘a eu.
Now leave us, the lot of you. I need to talk to Ned.
A présent, laissez—nous, tous. Il me faut parler avec Ned.
- Robert, my sweet... - Out, all of youl
- Robert, mon tendre... - Dehors. tous l
You damned fool.
Sois maudit.
Paper and ink on the table.
Papier et encre sur la table.
Write down what I say.
Ecris ce que je dis.
"In the name of Robert of the House Baratheon,
"Au nom de Robert dela Maison Baratheon,
"ﬁrst of..."
"premier du..."
You know how it goes.
Tu connais la suite.
Fill in the damn titles.
Remplis les maudits titres.
"I hereby command
"Je commande parla présente
"Eddard of House Stark..."
"Eddard de la Maison Stark..."
titles, titles...
titres, titres. . .
"upon my death,
"a ma mort.
"to rule in my stead
"de gouverner a ma place
"until my son Joffrey comes of age."
“jusqu‘à ce que mon ﬁls Joffrey ait l'âge de régner."
Give it over.
Donne-fe moi.
Give it to the council...
Donne-fe au conseil...
after I'm dead.
après ma mort.
At least they'll say I did this light,
Au moins. ils diront que j'ai bien fait
this one thing.
ce dernier acte.
You'll rule now.
Tu vas gouverner désormais.
You'll hate it worse than I did...
Tu détesteras ça encore plus que moi...
but you'll do it well.
mais tu t'en tireras très bien.
The girl...
La ﬁlle...
Daenerys.
Daenerys.
You were right. Varys, Littleﬁnger,
Tu avais raison. Varys, Littleﬁnger,
my brother... worthless.
mon frère... inutiles.
No one to tell me "no" but you.
Personne pour me dire "non" a part toi.
Only you.
Toi seul.
Let her live.
Laisse—la vivre.
Stop it, if it's not too late.
Arrête—les, si c'est encore possible.
And my son...
Et mon ﬁls...
help him, Ned.
aide—le, Ned.
Make him better than me.
Rends—le meilleur que moi.
I'll do everything I can to honour your memory.
Je ferai tout mon possible pour honorer ta mémoire.
My memory. (Laughs, coughs)
Ma mémoire.
King Robert Baratheon,
Le Roi Robert Baratheon,
murdered by a pig.
assassiné par un cochon.
Give me something for the pain and let me die.
Donne—moi quelque chose pour la douleur et laisse—moi mourir.
Give him milk of the poppy.
Donnez—lui du lait de pavot.
He was reeling from the wine.
II tenait a peine debout avec le vin.
He commanded us to...
Il nous a ordonné de...
step aside, but...
nous écarter, mais...
I failed him.
J'ai manqué a mes devoirs.
No man could have protected him from himself.
Personne ne pouvait le protéger de fui—mème.
I wonder, Ser Barristan,
Je me demande, Ser Barﬁstan,
who gave the king this wine?
quiaservicevinau roi?
His squire, from the king's own skin.
Son écuyer, de Ia gourde méme du roi.
His squire? The Lannister boy?
Son écuyer ? Le garçon Lannister ?
Such a dutiful boy to make sure His Grace
Tant de zèle a s‘assurer que Sa Majesté
did not lack refreshment.
soit toujours en mesure de se rafraîchir.
I do hope the poor lad does not blame himself.
J'espère que le pauvre garçon ne culpabilise pas.
His Grace has had a change of heart concerning Daenerys Targaryen.
Sa Majesté a changé d'avis concernant Daenerys Targaryen.
Whatever arrangements you made...
Quelles que soient les mesures que vous ayez prises...
unmake them. At once.
annulez—les. Tout de suite.
I'm afraid those birds have ﬂown.
Je crains que ce ne soit trop tard.
The girl is likely dead already.
La ﬁlle est probablement déja morte.
The stallion who mounts the world has no need for iron chairs.
L‘étalon qui montera le monde n‘a pas besoin de siège de fer.
Amording to the prophecy...
Selon la prophétie...
...the stallion will ride to the ends of the earth.
...l'étalon ira aux conﬁns du monde.
The earth ends at the black salt sea.
La terre s‘achève aux noirceurs de la mer salée.
No horse can cross the poison water.
Aucun cheval ne ﬁanchit l‘eau poison.
The earth does not end at the sea...
Le monde ne se termine pas a la mer...
...there are many dirts beyond the sea.
...il y a la poussière au—delè.
The dirt where I was born.
La poussière où je suis née.
Not dirts. Lands.
Pas poussière. Des terres.
Lands, yes. . .
Des terres. oui...
There are thousands of ships in the free cities.
Les cités libres ont des navires.
Wooden horses that ﬂy across the sea...
Des chevaux en bois pour traverser la mer...
Lets speak no more of wooden horses and iron chairs.
Assez parlé de sièges de fer et de chevaux en bois.
It's not a chair. It's a...
Ce n'est pas un siège. C‘est...
(Speaks English) ..throne.
..un trène.
(Speaks English) Throne.
Un trène.
A chair for a King to sit upon,
Un siège pour un Roi,
or...
ou...
...a Queen.
..une Reine.
A King does not need a chair to sit upon.
Un Roi n‘a pas besoin d'un siège.
He only needs a horse.
II a seulement besoin d'un cheval.
Can't you help me make him understand?
Peux—tu m‘aider a lui faire comprendre ?
The Dothraki do things in their own time, for their own reasons.
Les Dothraki font ce qu‘ils veulent quand ils le veulent.
Have patience, Khaleesi. We will go home, I promise you.
Soyez patiente. Khaleesi. Nous rentrerons, je vous le promets.
My brother was a fool, I know,
Mon frère était un idiot. je sais.
but he was the rightful heir to the Seven Kingdoms.
mais c'était l'héritier légitime des Sept Couronnes.
Have I said something funny, ser?
J'ai dit quelque chose de drôle, ser ?
Forgive me, Khaleesi. but your ancestor Aegon the Conqueror
Pardon, Khaleesi. mais votre ancêtre Aegon le Conquérant
didn't seize six of the Kingdoms bwause they were his right.
n‘a pas pris six des couronnes par droit.
He had no right to them. He seized them bwause he could.
Il n‘avait aucun droit. Il les a prises parce qu'il le pouvait.
And bwause he had dragons.
Parce qu'il avait des dragons.
Ah, well, having a few dragons makes things easier.
Posséder quelques dragons facilite les choses.
I believe what my eyes and ears report.
Je crois ce que mes yeux et mes oreilles me disent.
As for the rest... it was 300 years ago.
Et pour le reste… c'était il y a 300 ans.
Who knows what really happened?
Qui sait ce qu'il s‘est passé ?
Now if you'll pardon me, I'll seek out the merchant captain,
Pardonnez—moi, je dois trouver le eepitaine.
see if he has any letters for me.
voir s‘il a des lettres pour moi.
- I'll come with you. - No, no, don't trouble yourself.
- Je vous aœompagne. - Non, non, ne vous dérangez pas.
Enjoy the market. I'll rejoin you soon enough.
Amusez—vous. Je vous rejoindrai rapidement.
The Spider sends his greetings
L‘Araignée vous envoie ses vœux
and his congratulations.
et ses félicitations.
A royal pardon. You can go home now.
Un pardon royal. Vous pouvez rentrer chez vous a présent.
Sweet reds...
Rouges moelleux...
I have sweet reds from Lys, Volantis and the Arborl
J'ai des rouges moelleux de Lys, de Volantis et de La Treille I
Tyroshi pear brandyl Andalish soursl
Poire de Tyrosh | Des surets d‘Andal I
I have theml I have theml
J'en ai l J'en ai l
A taste for the Khaleesi?
Une larme pour la Khaleesi ?
I have a sweet red from Dorne, my lady.
J'ai un rouge moelleux de Dome, madame.
One taste and you'll name your ﬁrst child after me.
Une larme et vous donnerez mon nom a votre enfant.
(Speaks English) My son already has his name, but I'll try your summerwine.
Mon ﬁls a déja un nom, mais je goûterai votre vin d'été.
Just a taste.
Juste une larme.
My lady, you are from Westeros.
Madame, vous étes de Westeros.
You have the honour of addressing Daenerys of the House Targaryen.
Vous parlez a Daenerys de la Maison Targaryen.
Khaleesi of the Riding Men and Princess of the Seven Kingdoms.
Khaleesi des Seigneurs du Cheval et Princesse des Sept Couronnes.
- Princess. - Rise.
- Princesse. - Relevez—vous.
I'd still like to taste that wine.
J'aimerais goûter ce vin d'été.
That? Domish swill.
Ça ? Piquette de Dome.
Not worthy of a princess.
Indigne d‘une princesse.
IhaveadryredfromtheArbor-
J'ai un rouge sec de La Treille,
nectar of the gods.
un vrai nectar.
Let me give you a cask A... Agift.
Laissez—moi vous offrir un baril. Un... Un eedeau.
You honour me, ser.
Cest trop d'honneur, ser.
The honour... the honour is all mine.
L‘honneur... tout l‘honneur est pour moi.
You know, there are many in your homeland that pray for your return, Princess.
Beaucoup de gens dans votre pays prient pour votre retour.
I hope to repay your kindness someday.
J'espère vous remercier un jour.
Rakharo.
Rakharo.
Put down that cask
Repose ce baril.
- Is something wrong? - I have a thirst.
- Quelque chose ne va pas ? - J'ai soif.
Open it.
Ouvre—le.
The wine is for the khaleesi. It's not for the likes of you.
Cest pour la khaleesi. Pas pour vous.
Open it.
Ouvre—le.
Pour.
Verse.
It would be a crime to drink a wine this rich
Cest un crime de boire un vin de cette qualité
- without at least giving it time to breathe. - Do as he says.
- sans le laisser respirer. - Faites ce qu'il dit.
As the princess commands.
A vos ordres, Princesse.
Sweet, isn't it?
Moelleux. n'est—ce pas ?
Can you smell the fruit, ser?
Sentez—vous ce fruité. ser ?
Taste it, my lord.
Goûtez—le. monseigneur.
Tell me that that is not the ﬁnest wine that has ever touched your tongue.
Ce vin n‘est—il pas le plus délicat que vous ayez jamais bu.
You ﬁrst.
Toi d'abord.
Me?
Moi ?
I'm afraid I am not worthy of the vintage.
Je ne suis pas digne d'un tel cru.
Besides, it is a poor wine merchant who would drink up his own wares.
De plus. quel marchand de vin boit sa marchandise.
You will drink
Vous allez boire.
Stop himl
Arrêtez—le I
Come.
Venez.
- You came to us as outlaws... - (Thunder)
Vous étes venus a nous hors-la—loi.
..poachers, rapers,
braconniers, violeurs,
killers, thieves.
assassins, voleurs.
You came alone, in chains,
Vous étes venus a nous solitaires, enchainés,
or honour.
ou honneur.
You came to us rich and you came to us poor.
Vous étes venus a nous riches et vous étes venus a nous pauvres.
- (Thunder) - Some of you bear the names
Certains d‘entre vous portent le nom
of proud Houses,
d‘orgueilleuses Maisons,
others only bastard names or no names at all.
d'autres, des noms de bâtards ou pas de nom du tout.
It does not matter.
Cela n‘a aucune importance.
All that is in the past.
Cela relève d'un temps révolu.
on the Wall...
au Mur...
we are all one House.
nous formons tous une seule Maison.
- Tonight... - You're allowed to look happy.
- Ce soir... - Tu as le droit d'étre heureux
You're going to be a ranger.
Tu vas étre patrouilleur.
Isn't that what you always wanted?
Ce n'est pas ce que tu as toujours voulu ?
I want to ﬁnd my uncle.
Je veux trouver mon oncle.
I know he's alive out there. I know he is.
Je sais qu'il est en vie It!—bas. Je le sais.
I wish I could help you, but I'm no ranger.
Si seulement je pouvais t'aider, mais je ne suis pas patrouilleur.
It's the steward's life for me.
Je suis destiné a étre intendant.
There's honour in being a steward.
Cest un honneur d'étre intendant.
Not much, really.
Pas vraiment.
But there's food.
Mais on y trouve a manger.
Here...you begin anew.
Ici...vous repartez a neuf.
A man of the Night's Watch...
Un homme de la Garde de Nuit...
lives his life for the realm.
voue son ste«nce au royaume.
Not for a king...
Pas a un roi...
or a lord, or the honour of this House
ni a un suzerain. ou a l‘honneur de cette Maison
or that House,
ou de cette autre Maison,
not for gold or glory,
ni a l'or ou a la gloire,
or a woman's love,
ou a l‘amour d‘une femme,
but for the realm
mais au royaume
and all the people in it.
et a tous ses habitants.
You've all Ieamed the words of the vow.
Vous avez appris le texte de vos vœux.
Think refucally before you say them.
Méditez—le sérieusement avant de le dire.
The penalty for desertion...
La punition pour les déserteurs...
is death.
est la mort.
You can take your vows here...
Vous pouvez prononcer vos vœux icf...
tonight...
ce soir...
at sunset.
au coucher du soleil.
Do any of you still keep the old gods?
Est—il parmi vous un adepte des anciens dieux ?
I do, my lord.
Moi. monseigneur.
You'll want to take your vow before a heart tree as your uncle did.
Tu désires prêter ton serment devant un arbre—cœur comme ton oncle.
Yes, my lord.
Oui. monseigneur.
You'll ﬁnd a weirwood a mile north of the Wall.
Tu trouveras un bosquet de banals a un kilomètre au nord du Mur.
And your old gods too, maybe.
Ainsi que tes Vieux dieux. peut—étre.
My lord, might I go as well?
Monseigneur. puis-je y aller aussi ?
Does House Tarly keep the old gods?
La Maison Tarly vénère les anciens dieux ?
No, my lord.
Non, monseigneur.
I was named in the light of the Seven,
J'ai reçu mon nom dans la lumière des Sept,
as my father was and his father before him.
comme mon père et son père avant lui.
Why would you forsake the gods of your father and your House?
Pourquoi voudrais—tu abjurer les dieux de ton père et de ta Maison ?
The Night's Watch is my House now.
La Garde de Nuit est ma Maison a présent.
The Seven have never answered my prayers.
Les Sept n'ont jamais «ucé mes prières.
Perhaps the old gods will.
Peut—étre que les anciens dieux le feront.
As you wish, lad.
A ton aise. mon garçon.
You've all been assigned an order,
Nous avons affecté chacun d‘entre vous.
awording to our needs
compte tenu de nos besoins
and your strengths.
et de vos aptitudes.
Halder to the builders.
Haider, au génie.
Pyp to the stewards.
Pyp. a l‘intendance.
Toad to the builders. Grenn to the rangers.
Toad. au génie. Grenn. aux patrouilles.
Sanrwell to the stewards.
Sanrwell. a l‘intendance.
Matthar to the rangers. Dareon to the stewards.
Matthar. aux patrouilles. Dareon. a l‘intendance.
Balian to the rangers.
Balian, aux patrouilles.
Rast to the rangers.
Rast, aux patrouilles.
Jon to the stewards.
Jon, a l‘intendance.
Rancer to the builder.
Rancer. au génie.
Echiel to the builders. Gordo to the stewards.
Echiel, au génie. Gordo. a l‘intendance.
Niko to the rangers. Escan to the rangers.
Niko. aux patrouilles. Escan. aux patrouilles.
Vorkoy to the builders. Joby to the stables.
Vorkoy, au génie. Joby. aux écuries.
Mink to the kitchens. Allo to the builders.
Mink. aux cuisines. Allo. au génie.
Nelugo to the rangers.
Nelugo. aux patrouilles.
May all the gods preserve you.
Puissent tous les dieux vous préserver.
Rangers with me.
Les patrouilleurs, suivez—moi.
Buildersl
Les ingénieurs I
Samwell, you will assist me in the rookery and library.
Sanrwell. tu m‘assisteras a la bibliothèque et a la roukerfe.
Pyp, you will report to Bowen Marsh in the kitchens.
Pyp. tu te présenteras a Bowen Marsh en cuisine.
Luke, report to One-Eyed Joe in the stables.
Luke. tu te présenteras a Joe le Borgne a l'écurie.
Dareon, we are sending you to Eastwatch.
Dareon. nous t‘envoyons a Fort—Levant.
Present yourself to Borcas when you arrive.
Présente—toi a Borcas dès ton arrivée.
Make no comment about his nose.
Ne fais pas de commentaire sur son nez.
Jon Snow, Lord Commander Morrnont
Jon Snow. Lord Commandant Morrnont
has requested you for his personal steward.
t'a requis pour son service personnel.
Will I serve the Lord Commander's meals and fetch hot water for his bath?
Je servirai les repas du Lord Commandant et l‘eau chaude pour son bain ?
Certainly. And keep a ﬁre burning in his chambers,
Certes. Et tu entretiendras le feu dans ses appartements,
change his sheets and blankets daily
tu changeras ses draps et ses couvertures tous les jours
and do everything else the Lord Commander requires of you.
et tu exécuteras les ordres du Lord Commandant.
Do you take me for a servant?
Me prenez—vous pour un larbin ?
We took you for a man of the Night's Watch.
Nous t‘avons pris pour un homme de la Garde de Nuit.
But perhaps we were wrong in that.
Mais nous avions peut—étre tort.
- May I go? - As you wish.
- Puis-je disposer ? - A ta guise.
Jon, waitl Don't you see what they're doing?
Jon, attends I Ne vois—tu pas ce qu‘ils font ?
I see Ser Alliser's revenge, that's all.
Je ne vois que la vengeance de Ser Alliser.
He wanted it and he got it.
Il l‘a voulue et il l‘a eue.
Stewards are nothing but maidsl
Les intendants ne sont que des domestiques I
I'm a better swordsman and rider than any of youl
Je suis meilleur bretteur et cavalier que vous tous l
I was singing for a high lord at Acorn Hall
Je chantais pour un grand seigneur a la Glandée
when he put his hand on my leg and he wanted to see my cock
quand il a mis sa main sur ma jambe et demanda a voir ma queue.
I pushed him away and he said he'd have my hands out off for stealing their silver.
Je l'ai repoussé. II a dit qu'il me ferait
So now I'm here - at the end of the world
Je suis ici, a l‘autre bout du monde
with no one to sing for but old men and little shits like you.
avec des vieillards et des petites merdes comme toi.
I'll never see my family again.
Je ne revenai jamais ma famille.
I'll never be inside a woman again.
Je ne coucherai jamais plus avec une femme.
So don't tell me about fair.
Ne me parle pas d‘injustice.
I thought you were caught stealing a wheel of cheese for your starving sister.
Je croyais que tu avais volé du fromage pour ta sœur aﬁamée.
Think I was gonna tell a bunch of strangers that a high lord tried to grab my cock?
J'allais pas raconter a des étrangers qu'un seigneur a attrapé ma queue.
Could you sing me a song, Pyp? I'd like to hear a song.
Peux—tu me chanter quelque chose, Pyp ? J'aimerais entendre une chanson.
Now listen to me.
A présent, æoute-moi.
The old man is the Lord Commander of the Night's Watch.
Le Vieil homme est le Lord Commandant de la Garde de Nuit.
You'll be with him day and night.
Tu seras a ses cotés jour et nuit.
Yes, you'll clean his clothes.
Oui. tu nettoieras ses vêtements.
But you'll also take his letters, attend him at meetings,
Mais tu prendras son courrier. tu assisteras aux réunions,
squire for him in battle.
tu seras son écuyer dans la bataille.
You'll know everything, be part of everything.
Tu sauras tout, tu prendras part a tout.
And he asked for you himself.
Et il t'a réclamé fui—mème.
He wants to groom you for command.
Il veut te bichonner pour le commandement.
ljust...
Cest juste. ..
I always wanted to be a ranger.
Je voulais étre patrouilleur.
Ialwayswantedtobeawizard.
Je voulais étre un sorcier.
No, I'm serious.
Non, je suis sérieux.
So you'll stay and say your words with me?
Tu restes et nous prononcerons nos vœux ensemble ?
Lord Stark...a moment.
Lord Stark..un instant.
Alone, if you will.
Seul. si possible.
He named you Protector of the Realm.
II vous a nommé Protecteur du Royaume.
He did.
En effet.
She won't car'e.
Elle ne s‘en souciera pas.
Give me an hour and I can put a hundred swords at your command.
Donnez—moi une heure et je vous trouve cent hommes.
And what should I do with a hundred swords?
Que dois-je faire avec cent hommes ?
Strikel Tonight, while the castle sleeps.
Frapper | Ce soir, quand le château est endormi.
We must get Joffrey away from his mother and into our custody.
II faut séparer Joffrey de sa mère et s‘emparer de lui.
Protector of the Realm or no, he who holds the king holds the kingdom.
Protecteur ou non, l‘homme qui tient le roi tient le royaume.
Every moment you delay gives Cersei another moment to prepare.
Chaque instant perdu donne a Cersei le temps de se préparer.
By the time Robert dies, it will be too late for the both of us.
Lorsque Robert mouna. il sera trop tard pour nous deux
What about Stannis?
Et Stannis ?
Saving the Seven Kingdoms from Cersei and delivering them to Stannis?
Sauver les Sept Couronnes de Cersei pour les conﬁer a Stannis ?
You have odd notions about protecting the realm.
Vous avez de curieuses façons de protéger le royaume.
Stannis is your older brother.
Stannis est votre frère aîné.
This isn't about the bloody line of suwession.
Au diable l‘ordre de suœession.
That didn't matter when you rebelled against the Mad King. It shouldn't matter now.
II importait peu pendant la rébellion contre le Roi Fou. De méme aujourd'hui.
What's best for the Kingdoms?
Qu‘est-il préférable pour les Couronnes ?
What's best for the people we rule?
Qu‘est-il préférable pour le peuple que nous gouvemons ?
We all know what Stannis is.
Nous connaissons tous Stannis.
He inspires no love or loyalty.
II n'inspire ni amour ni loyauté.
He's not a king.
Ce n'est pas un roi.
Stannis is a commander.
Stannis est un commandant.
He's led men into war twice.
II a mené des hommes au combat deux fois.
He destroyed the Greyjoy ﬁeet.
II a détruit la ﬂotte des Gœyjoy.
Yes, he's a good soldier. Everyone knows that. So was Robert.
Cest un bon soldat. Cest connu. Robert l‘était aussi.
Tell me something.
Dites—moi.
Do you still believe good soldiers make good kings?
Croyez—vous qu'un bon soldat fasse un bon roi?
I will not dishonour Robert's last hours by shedding blood in his halls...
Je ne temirai pas les dernières heures de Robert en versant du sang icf...
and dragging ﬁightened children from their beds.
et en anachant des enfants apeurés de leurs lits.
You will sail to Dragonstone tonight.
Tu partiras en bateau pour Peyredragon ce soir.
You will place this in the hand of Stannis Baratheon.
Tu remettras ca en main propre a Stannis Baratheon.
Not his steward...
Pas a son intendant...
not his ptacain of the guard...
pas a son eepitaine de garde...
and not his wife.
et pas a sa femme.
Only Stannis himself.
Seulement a Stannis en personne.
Now leave us.
Pars maintenant.
My Lord Protector.
Mon Lord Protecteur.
The king has no truebom sons.
Le roi n‘a pas de ﬁls légitime.
Joffrey and Tommen...
Joffrey et Tommen...
are Jaime Lannisters bastards.
sont les batards de Jaime Lannister.
- So when the king dies... - The throne passes to his brother...
- Alors quand le roi mourra... - Le trène ira a son frère...
Lord Stannis.
Lord Stannis.
So it would seem.
Selon toute apparence.
- Unless... - There is no "unless".
- A moins. - Il n‘y a pas de "a moins".
He is the rightful heir. Nothing can change that.
C‘est l'héritier légitime. C‘est indiscutable.
And he cannot take the throne without your help.
II ne peut prendre le trène sans votre aide.
You would be wise to deny it to him and to make sure Joffrey suweeds.
Il serait sage de la lui refuser
Do you have a shred of honour?
Avez—vous un brin d‘honneur ?
You are now Hand of the King and Protector of the Realm.
Vous étes la Main du Roi et le Protecteur du Royaume.
All of the power is yours. You need only...
Le pouvoir vous appartient. II vous sufﬁt...
reach out and take it.
de tendre le bras et de le prendre.
Make peace with the Lannisters.
Faites la paix avec les Lannister.
Release the Imp. Wed your daughter to Joffrey.
Relèchez le Lutin. Unissez votre ﬁlle a Joffrey.
We've plenty of time to get rid of Stannis,
Nous nous débanasserons de Stannis,
and if Joffrey seems likely to cause problems when he comes into his throne,
et si Joffrey devient un problème quand il aœédera au pouvoir.
we simply reveal his little secret
nous divulguerons son petit secret
- and seat Lord Renly there instead. - We?
- et couronnemns Lord Renly a sa place. - Nous ?
You'll need someone to share these burdens, I assure you.
Vous aurez besoin de quelqu'un pour partager ce fardeau. croyez—moi.
My price would be modest.
Mon prix sera modique.
What you suggest is treason.
Ce que vous suggérez s'appelle de la trahison.
Make peace with the Lannisters, you say...
Faites la paix avec les Lannister, dites—vous...
with the people who tried to murder my boy.
ceux qui ont essayé de tuer mon garçon.
We only make peace with our enemies, my lord.
Nous ne faisons la paix qu'avec nos ennemis. monseigneur.
That's why it's called "making peace".
Cest pour cela qu'on dit “faire la paix“.
No. I won't do it.
Non. Je ne la ferai pas.
So it will be Stannis and war?
Alors, ce sera Stannis et la guerre ?
There is no other choice.
Nous n'avons pas le choix
He is the heir.
Cest l'héritier.
So why did you call me here?
Pourquoi m'avoir convoqué ?
Not for my wisdom, clearly.
Pas pour mes conseils, apparemment.
You promised Catelyn you would help me.
Vous avez promis a Çatelyn de m'aider.
The queen has a dozen knights and a hundred men-at-arms -
La reine a une douzaine de chevaliers et une centaine d‘hommes.
enough to overwhelm what remains of my household guard.
Cest sufﬁsant pour écraser ce qui reste de ma garde personnelle.
I need the gold cloaks.
J'ai besoin des manteaux d‘or.
The City Watch is 2,000 strong...
Le Guet comprend 2 000 hommes...
and sworn to defend the king's peace.
qui ont juré de défendre la paix du roi.
Look at you.
Regardez—vous.
You know what you want me to do,
Vous savez ce que vous voulez de moi.
you know it has to be done,
vous savez que c'est nœeæaire,
but it's not honourable, so...
mais ce n'est pas honorable, alors...
the words stick in your throat.
vous n'arrivez pas a le dire.
When the queen proclaims one king
Quand la reine proclame un roi
and the Hand proclaims another,
et que la Main en proclame un autre.
whose peace do the gold cloaks protect?
quelle paix les manteaux d'or vont—ils protéger ?
Who do they follow
Qui vont—ils suivre ?
The man who pays them.
L‘homme qui les paye.
(Jon and Sanrwell) Hear my words and bear witness to my vow.
Oyez mes paroles et soyez témoins de mon serment.
Night gathers and now my watch begins.
La nuit se regroupe et voici que débute ma garde.
It shall not end until my death.
Jusqu'à ma mort. je la monterai.
I shall take no wife,
Je ne prendrai femme,
hold no lands, father no children.
ne tiendrai terres. n‘engendrerai.
I shall wear no crowns and win no glory.
Je ne porterai de couronne. n‘acquerrai de gloire.
I shall live and die at my post.
Je vivrai et mounai a mon poste.
I am the sword in the darkness.
Je suis l'épée dans les ténèbres.
I am the watcher on the walls.
Je suis le veilleur au rempart.
I am the shield that guards the realms of men.
Je suis le bouclier protecteur des royaumes humains.
I pledge my life and honour to the Night's Watch,
Je voue mon ste«nce et mon honneur a la Garde de Nuit,
for this night and all the nights to come.
pour cette nuit et pour toutes les nuits a venir.
You knelt as boys.
Vous vous étes agenouillés enfants.
Rise now as men of the Night's Watch.
Relevez—vous hommes de la Garde de Nuit.
Well done. Well done.
Félicitations. Félicitations.
To me, Ghost. Bring it here.
Ici, Fantôme. Apporte.
Gods be goodl
Bonté divine I
What will they do to him?
Que va—t—il lui arriver ?
When the khalasar rides, he'll be leashed to a saddle
Ils I‘attacheront a une selle
and forced to run behind the horses for as long as he can.
et le feront courir derrière les chevaux aussi longtemps qu'il le peut.
And when he falls?
Et lorsqu'il tombera ?
I saw a man last nine miles once.
J'ai vu un homme tenir 15 kilomètres.
King Robert still wants me dead.
Le Roi Robert me veut morte.
This poisoner was the ﬁrst. He won't be the last.
Cet empoisonneur est le premier, pas le dernier.
I thought he'd leave me alone now that my brother is gone.
Je pensais qu'il me laisserait tranquille a présent que mon frère est mort.
He will never leave you alone.
II ne vous laissera jamais tranquille.
If you ride to darkest Asshai, his assassins will follow you.
Si vous chevauchez vers Asshai. ses assassins vous suivront.
If you sailed all the way to the Basilisk Isles,
Si vous naviguez jusqu‘aux Îles du Basilic,
He will never abandon the hunt.
II n‘abandonnera jamais la chasse.
You're a Targaryen - the last Targaryen.
Vous étes une Targaryen. la dernière des Targaryens.
Your son will have Targaryen blood
Votre ﬁls aura du sang Targaryen
with 40,!!!) riders behind him.
escorté par 40 000 cavaliers.
He will not have my son.
II ne tuera pas mon ﬁls.
He will not have you either, Khaleesi.
II ne vous tuera pas non plus. Khaleesi.
Moon of my life.
Lune de mes jours.
Are you hurt?
Es—tu blessée ?
Jorah the Andal.
Jorah l‘Andal.
I heard what you did.
on m‘a dit ce que tu as fait.
Choose any horse you wish, it is yours.
Choisi le cheval que tu veux. il t‘appartient.
I make this gift to you.
Cest mon eedeau.
And to my son, the stallion who will mount the world,
A mon ﬁls. l‘étalon qui montera le monde,
I will also pledge a gift.
je lui promets un eedeau.
I will give him the iron chair...
je lui promets le siège de fer...
...that his mother's father sat upon.
...sur lequel le père de sa mère s‘assit.
I will give him Seven Kingdoms.
Je lui donnerai les Sept Couronnes.
I, Drogo, will do this.
Moi. Drogo, je m‘y engage.
I will take my Khalasar west to where the world ends...
J‘emmènerai mon khalasar vers l‘ouest au rebord du monde...
...and ride wooden horses across the black salt water...
...et je traverserai la mer salée noire sur les chevaux en bois...
- ...as no Khal has done before. - (Men cheering)
...ce qu‘aucun Khal n‘a jamais fait.
I will kill the men in iron suits...
Je tuerai les hommes en costumes de fer...
- ...and tear down their stone houses. - (Cheering)
...et je détruirai leurs maisons de pierres.
- I will rape their women...
Je violerai leurs femmes...
...take their children as slaves...
...je ferai de leurs enfants des esclaves...
...and bring their broken gods back to Vaes Dothrak
...et je rapporterai leurs dieux brisés a Vaes Dothrak
This, I vow...
Je le jure...
...I, Drogo, son of Bharbo.
...moi, Drogo, ﬁls de Bharbo.
I swear before the Mother of Mountains...
Je jure devant la Mère des Montagnes...
...as the stars look down in witness.
...que les astres en soient témoins.
As the stars look down in witness.
que les astres en soient témoins.
Lord Starkl
Lord Starkl
It's all right. Let him through.
C‘est bon. Laissez—le passer.
Lord Stark King Joffrey and the Queen Regent request your presence in the Throne Room.
le Roi Joffrey et la reine régente
King Joffrey?
Le Roi Joffrey?
King Robert is gone.
Le Roi Robert est mort.
The gods give him rest.
Qu'il repose en paix.
All is awomplished. The City Watch is yours.
Tout est prét. Le Guet est a vous.
ls Lord Renly joining us?
Lord Renly se joint-ll a nous ?
I fear Lord Renly has left the city.
J'ai bien peur que Lord Renly n‘ait quitté la ville.
He rode through the Old Gate an hour before dawn
II est passé parla Vieille porte une heure avant le lever du jour
with Ser Loras Tyrell and some 50 retainers.
avec Ser Loras Tyrell et 50 hommes.
Last seen galloping south in some haste.
Aperçu pour la dernière fois, galopant en direction du sud.
We stand behind you, Lord Stark.
Nous sommes a vos cotés, Lord Stark
(Steward) All hail His Grace,
Hommage et salut a Sa Majesté,
Joffrey of Houses Baratheon and Lannister,
Joffrey des Maisons Baratheon et Lannister,
the First of His Name,
premier du nom,
King of the Andals and the First Men,
Roi des Andals et des Premiers Hommes.
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms
Seigneur des Sept Couronnes
and Protector of the Realm.
et Protecteur du Royaume.
I command the council to make all nmessary arrangements for my coronation.
J‘ordonne au conseil de prendre les dispositions pour mon couronnement.
I wish to be crowned within the fortnight.
Je veux étre couronné sous 15 jours.
Today I shall accept oaths of fealty
A présent, je vais accueillir les serments de ﬁdélité
from my loyal councillors.
de mes loyaux conseillers.
Ser Barristan...
Ser Barﬁstan...
I believe no man here could ever question your honour.
Personne ici ne peut douter de votre honneur.
King Robert's seal - unbroken.
Le sceau du Roi Robert, non brisé.
"Lord Eddard Stark is herein named...
"Lord Eddard Stark est parla présente nommé...
"Protector of the Realm...
"Protecteur du Royaume...
"to rule as regent...
"assurera les fonctions de régent...
"until the heir come of age."
“jusqu‘à ce que l'héritier en ait l'âge."
May I see that letter, Ser Barristan?
Puis-je voir cette lettre, Ser Barﬁstan ?
Protector of the Realm.
Protecteur du Royaume.
Is this meant to be your shield, Lord Stark?
Serait—ce la votre bouclier, Lord Stark ?
A pime of paper?
Un bout de papier ?
- Those were the king's words. - We have a new king now.
- Ce sont les mots du roi. - Nous avons un nouveau roi a présent.
Lord Eddard, when we last spoke you offered me some counsel.
Lors de notre dernier entretien. vous m‘avez conseillée.
Allow me to return the courtesy.
Permettez—moi de vous rendre la politesse.
Bend the knee, my lord.
A genoux. monseigneur.
Bend the knee and swear loyalty to my son...
A genoux et jurez ﬁdélité a mon ﬁls...
and we shall allow you to live out your days
et nous vous laisserons vivre dans les terres sinistres
Your son has no claim to the throne.
Votre ﬁls n‘a aucun droit au trène.
- (Snorts) - Liarl
Menteur I
You condemn yourself with your own mouth, Lord Stark.
Vous vous condamnez vous—mème.
Ser Barristan, seize this traitor.
Ser Barﬁstan, saisissez ce traître.
Ser Barristan is a good man, a loyal man. Do him no harm.
Ser Barﬁstan est un homme bon et loyal. Ne le blessez pas.
You think he stands alone?
Vous croyez qu'il est seul ?
Kill himl Kill all oftheml I command itl
Tuez—le I Tuez—les tous | Je l'ordonne I
Commanderl Take the queen and her children into custody.
Commandant I Arrêtez la reine et ses enfants.
Escort them back to the royal apartments and keep them there, under guard.
Esoortez—les jusqu‘à leurs appartements et qu‘ils y soient gardés.
Men of the Watchl
Hommes du Guet I
I want no bloodshed.
Je ne veux pas de sang.
Tell your men to lay down their swords.
Dites a vos hommes de déposer leurs armes.
No one needs to die.
Personne ne doit mourir.
(Commander) Nowl
Maintenant I
I did warn you not to trust me.
Je vous avais dit de ne pas me faire conﬁance.